favourite celebrations
những lễ hội yêu thích
Simone is a photographer. Last year she visited many countries.
Simone là một nhiếp ảnh gia. Năm ngoái cô ấy đã đến thăm nhiều quốc gia.
She asked some children about their favourite celebrations.
Cô ấy đã hỏi một số trẻ em về những lễ hội yêu thích của chúng.
Hu Jingjing lives in China and her favourite celebration is New Year.
Hu Jingjing sống ở Trung Quốc và lễ hội yêu thích của bạn ấy là Năm Mới.
First she decorates the house with red lanterns, cards from friends and paintings of flowers and birds.
Đầu tiên bạn ấy trang trí nhà bằng đèn lồng đỏ, thiệp từ bạn bè và tranh vẽ hoa và chim.
Then Hu Jingjing has a bath and puts on new clothes.
Sau đó Hu Jingjing tắm và mặc quần áo mới.
After that she eats a big meal with all her family and her parents give her a present.
Sau đó bạn ấy ăn một bữa lớn với cả gia đình và bố mẹ tặng bạn ấy một món quà.
It's always a little red packet with money inside.
Nó luôn là một bao lì xì nhỏ màu đỏ có tiền bên trong.
Finally at 12 o'clock the bells ring and there are many beautiful and noisy fireworks.
Cuối cùng lúc 12 giờ chuông reo và có rất nhiều pháo hoa đẹp và rộn ràng.
Hu Jingjing likes New Year because she goes to bed very late.
Hu Jingjing thích Năm Mới vì bạn ấy được đi ngủ rất muộn.
João lives in Brazil and his favourite celebration is Carnival because he plays the drums in the Carnival procession.
João sống ở Brazil và lễ hội yêu thích của bạn ấy là Lễ hội Hóa trang vì bạn ấy chơi trống trong đoàn diễu hành.
João goes to a samba school with his sister.
João đi đến trường samba cùng chị gái.
He learns the drums and she learns dancing. They have to practice every day.
Bạn ấy học trống và chị ấy học nhảy. Họ phải tập luyện mỗi ngày.
In the Carnival procession there are hundreds of drummers and dancers all dressed up in beautiful clothes.
Trong đoàn diễu hành Lễ hội có hàng trăm tay trống và vũ công mặc quần áo đẹp.
Many people watch them and everyone is very happy.
Nhiều người xem họ và ai cũng rất vui.
João loves the fireworks at the end of the procession.
João rất thích pháo hoa ở cuối đoàn diễu hành.
Noha lives in Egypt and her favourite celebration is Shamm el-Nasim.
Noha sống ở Ai Cập và lễ hội yêu thích của bạn ấy là Shamm el-Nasim.
She likes it because there is no school on that day, her parents don't work and she has a lovely day with all her family.
Bạn ấy thích vì hôm đó không phải đi học, bố mẹ không đi làm và bạn ấy có một ngày tuyệt vời với cả gia đình.
It's at the start of spring. The weather is good and there are beautiful flowers everywhere.
Nó vào đầu mùa xuân. Thời tiết đẹp và có hoa đẹp khắp nơi.
Noha and her brother get up early and paint eggs.
Noha và anh trai dậy sớm và tô màu trứng.
Then they go for a walk next to the river and watch people in their boats.
Sau đó họ đi dạo bên sông và xem mọi người trên thuyền.
After that they have a picnic and in the afternoon they visit the zoo.
Sau đó họ đi dã ngoại và buổi chiều họ đi sở thú.
Noha loves seeing all the animals. Her favourite animals are the turtles.
Noha rất thích xem các con vật. Động vật yêu thích của bạn ấy là rùa.
Next year Simone is going to visit lots more countries.
Năm tới Simone sẽ đến thăm nhiều quốc gia hơn.
She's going to talk to more children and she's going to take more photos.
Cô ấy sẽ nói chuyện với nhiều trẻ em hơn và chụp nhiều ảnh hơn.
Please write to Simone and tell her about your favourite celebration.
Hãy viết thư cho Simone và kể cho cô ấy nghe về lễ hội yêu thích của bạn.